Hello friends, my name is Anil Rajpat.
I am the founder of Family Fund Financial Services. I have an
MBA in Finance and have been
working in the corporate sector for 14 years. Today I am presenting to you
a term insurance plan from Bandhan Life Insurance. Even
if you are a 12th pass or your
income is 2.5 lakh, you
can still take a term plan. The name of this plan is iTerm
Prime Karke Bandhan Life, which you previously
knew as Aegon Life. It has
now become Bandhan Life from April 19, 2024.
For more information about the plan, watch the full video. If you
like the video, please visit my
YouTube channel. A person up to 2 years of age can purchase this policy.
If you pay regular premium, then
this person up to 65 years of age can
purchase the policy. If you
keep the premium payment for 10 years, then the
maximum entry is 50 years. And if you opt for a 15 year
premium payment term, then a
person up to 45 years can purchase this policy.
Talking about the policy term, the
minimum policy term in regular pay will be 5 years.  If you
pay premium for 10 years, the
policy term will be 15 years. If you pay for 15 years, the
policy term will be 20 years.
If you pay at the age of 60, the policy term will be till 65 years
and the maximum policy
term will be 70 minus your entry. If we talk about the
premium payment term in the policy, then
here you can pay regular premium, you can pay
premium for 10 years, you can
take premium payment for 15 years or
you can pay till the age of 60.
Talking about the minimum sum assured, if we talk about the minimum insurance cover, then
this policy starts from 25 lakhs. There is
no maximum limit, so
you can also take an insurance cover of 25 lakhs in it.
From 25 lakhs to
49.99 lakhs, when you purchase the policy, then
you should be 10th pass and
even if your income is 8 lakhs, you will be able to purchase the policy.
For sums above this,
standard income and education proof will be required.
Another great feature provided by SV is
Smart Exit Value. Smart Exit
Value means that when you reach the age of 55
or above, you
can withdraw all the premiums paid, close the policy, and exit the policy. To
avail this benefit from your policy,
when you purchase the policy, your
minimum age at the time of inception should be
40 years or less, and the policy
term should be up to the age of 70, only then
you can exercise this option. As for the
maturity benefit in this policy, since this is a
pure term policy, there is
no maturity benefit in it. Talking about the death
benefit, in the death benefit, you will get the basic
sum of Rs. 105 on the total premium paid or 11
times the annual premium, whichever is higher. The
higher will always be the basic sum
method, so you will get that on death.
You will also get riders in this policy. There is
also a rider for accidental death benefit and a rider for
critical illness benefit.  You
can also add riders to the policy as per your needs. Now let us understand this
product, Bandhan Life, or Aegon Life,
which is a term plan.
If a 35-year-old purchases this policy by priming it, then
understand the benefit illustration. The policy term is also 35 years
and the premium payment term is regular for
35 years, which means that
their insurance cover will continue till the age of 70 for ₹1 lakh.
Here, their premium will be ₹
6370, where GST will be ₹
1117. With GST,
their first year's premium will be ₹7517
and the premium for the remaining years will be ₹83
because the customer will get a discount here in the first year. So, even
if the customer
is a DV pass and their income is ₹2.5 lakh, they can still
purchase this policy. Now, if the
customer wants to pay premium for
only 10 years instead of
paying premium for the full 35 years, they can select this option,
but they want cover till the age of 70.  If the person has an
insurance cover of Rs 25 lakh and his income is Rs 8 lakh, then
his premium for the first year will be Rs
16315 and for the remaining nine years the
premium is Rs 187. He can purchase this policy.
If he wants to add a rider, then a
rider is also available in this policy,
he can get it done. This is how this
policy will work.
Talking about other benefits and
features of the policy, loan facility
is not available in this policy because it is a pure term
policy. You will get income tax benefit.
You get rebate on premium up to Rs 1 lakh in Income Tax Section ATC. Plus,
death benefit is always tax free.
Talking about the free period, there will be a
free look period of 15 days. If you
take the policy in electronic mode, then you
also get the option of a free look period of 30 days. If you
want to get the money back by cancelling the policy, then you can do it after getting a free look.
Talking about surrender benefit,
surrender benefit is not available in this policy.
Talking about revival period, then this
If for some reason you are unable to pay the premium on time in the policy
and want to revive it, then
you can revive it. The revival period in this is 5 years.
If I were to
compare this plan, then this is a good plan. It is a
cheap plan. It is a term plan which
fulfils many of your needs. You are
also given different premium options.
Insurance cover starts from 25 lakhs.
This plan is available even if you have passed 10th standard.
This policy is also available on income of 8 lakhs. Along with this,
you can also avail surrogate benefit. For
example, if you have a car, you have a car ID, you have a
credit card, you have investment in mutual funds, you have
FD. Then you can purchase this policy by giving this type of
surrogate income proof.
To purchase this plan from me, you can compare the
best plan by whatsapp2. If you
want to purchase more, then I already have
more than 3 videos on YouTube which will
help you in your insurance related financial planning. Thank you so much
Jai
Hind and